So let's take a quick look at how grid and flexbox can work together.
让我们快速看一看如何将 grid 和 flexbox 组合在一起使用
To start, I'm going to show you an example that I've
在开始 我会先向你展示一个现成的例子
made and take you through it quickly,
快速过一遍它
but the truth is, you're going to learn how to build
然后在这节课程中
this up step-by-step throughout the lesson.
你会一步一步的学习如何搭建它
As you can see here,
这里你可以看到
I've set up a grid using a container.
我将一个容器设置成了 grid 布局
The first thing I've done is I've set the display to grid.
第一件我们需要做的事情是设置 display 属性为 grid
We'll go through the columns and rows coming up.
待会儿我们会看一看其中的行和列
You can see I've set grid template areas,
在这里我们设置了 grid-template-areas 属性
and here, each box uses the display flex.
然后每个 box 也设置了 display 属性为 flex
Here's our HTML, three boxes, inside a container.
这是我们的 HTML 代码：container 容器内部有 3 个 box 元素
The container has a display of grid and each box has a display of flex.
container 容器的 display 属性为 grid 而每个 box 的 display 属性则是 flex
That's what's putting these words here in the middle.
这就是为什么这些文字会居中显示
If you see, once we take flex away,
如果我们去掉 flex 的话
all of our content is put back up into the top left-hand corner.
所有的内容会重新回到左上角的位置
However, with flex, we can center them easily.
使用 flex 的话 我们可以轻易的居中它们
Now, there's just one more trick I want to show you,
现在 我要向你展示一个小技能
and this one makes me really excited.
一个非常有趣的技能
So as you can see in our grid here,
在我们的 grid 容器中
the distribution is a little funny.
内容的分布看起来不太好看
Everything is kind of leaning to the left, but grid,
所有的内容都是靠左显示
like flex, allows you to justify your content using justify content.
grid 和 flex 一样 我们可以通过 justify-content 居中内容
In this case, I want to see centered.
在这个例子中 我们设置为 center
So let's save that and then look at that.
然后保存一下看看会发生什么
Now we have a beautiful laid out grid,
好了 现在我们有了一个漂亮的网格布局
two columns and two rows,
两行和两列
all put beautifully in the middle.
全部都居中显示
This is just one example of what you can do using CSS grid and flexbox together.
这就是一个你可以将 CSS grid 和 flexbox 结合起来使用的例子